活埋
Hey!
Help!
救命！
Help! Help!
救命！ 救命！
Fuck.
操
Okay, okay, okay. Okay.
冷静，冷静，冷静
Okay. What was it? What's the number?What's the number?
这是什么语？号码是多少？号码是多少？
1-2-1...
1-2-1…
Fuck!
操！
Where is it?
怎么不见了？
- 911. Please hold.- No! Wait! Please!
- 正在转接911，请稍候- 别，等一下！求你了！
- Yes. 911.- Hello. I'm buried.
- 这里是911- 你好，我被活埋了
You have to help me. You have to help me.I can't breathe.
你一定要救救我，一定要救救我我没法呼吸了
- Sir?- I'm buried in a coffin. Please, help.
- 先生？- 我被埋在一个棺材里，请救救我
- Send someone to find me.- Sir, slow down.
- 派人来找我- 先生，请慢点说
- What is your name?- Paul. Paul Conroy.
- 您叫什么名字？- 保罗，保罗・康罗伊
Okay, Mr. Conroy.Can you tell me your location?
好的，康罗伊先生，您能告诉我您的位置吗？
I don't know. I'm in a coffin.
我不知道，我被困在一个棺材里
I don't know where. Please, help.I'm scared.
我不知道这是哪，请救救我，我好害怕
- You're in a coffin?- Yes.
- 您在一个棺材里？- 是的
It's like one of those old, wooden ones.
就像是那种老式的木制棺材
- Are you at a funeral home?- No. No. No.
- 请问您在殡仪馆吗？- 不，不，不是
I don't know. No.
我也不知道在哪
- How are you calling me right now?- What?
- 那您现在是怎么给我打电话的呢？- 什么？
If you're buried in a coffin,where are you calling me from?
如果您被埋在一个棺材里那您怎么给我打的电话？
From a cell phone.There was an old cell phone in the coffin.
用手机，棺材里有一个旧手机
- You're calling me from your cell phone?- Yes.
- 您在用您的手机给我打电话？- 是的
Yes. Yes. No, no. It's not my cell phone,
对，对，哦，不对，这不是我的手机
but, yes, I'm calling from a cell phone.
但我的确是用手机打的电话
There was a cell phone in the coffinwhen you climbed in?
您爬进棺材的时候里面就有一个手机？
Yes. What?
是的，什么？
- I didn't climb in, though.- How did you end up in the coffin, sir?
- 不是我自己爬进来的- 那您是怎么进去的，先生？
- I was put here.- In the coffin?
- 我是被别人弄进来的- 弄进棺材里？
Yes. Please, help.
对，求你救救我
- And you're saying the coffin is buried?- Yes. Yeah.
- 您是说过棺材被埋了？- 是的
I'm a truck driver. I'm an American.
我是一个卡车司机，一个美国人
It's hot in here and I can't breathe.
这里面好热，我快没法呼吸了
- Please.- Do you know your location, sir?
- 求你了- 先生，您知道您位置吗？
- I told you, somewhere in Iraq. Please, help.- Iraq?
- 我说过不知道，反正是在伊拉克，救我- 伊拉克？
Yes. I'm a truck driver. I'm an American.I work for CRT.
对，我是一个卡车司机，我是美国人我为CRT公司工作
- Are you a soldier, sir?- No, please, you have to listen to me.
- 先生，您是士兵吗？- 不是，请你认真听我说
I'm a truck driver. I'm an American.
我是一个卡车司机，我是美国人
I'm a cvilian contractor working in Iraq.We were attacked in Baqubah.
我是在伊拉克的普通合同工我们在巴古拜被人袭击了
And they... They shot all of them.
他们枪杀了所有的人
- They shot who, sir?- All of the other drivers.
- 先生，他们杀了谁？- 其他所有司机
And you are saying this happened in Iraq?The country?
您说这发生在伊拉克？在伊拉克这个国家？
Yeah. Please, listen to me, okay?Listen to me.
对，请你听我说，听我说行吗？
They gave me a safety number and it was inmy wallet, and I don't know where it is now.
他们给了我一个安全号码我把它放在钱包里，但现在不见了
Mr. Conroy, this is 911 emergencyin Youngstown, Ohio.
康罗伊先生这里是俄亥俄州扬斯敦市911紧急热线
- Ohio?- Yes, sir.
- 俄亥俄州？- 是的，先生
I'm not sure exactly how you called here
我不清楚为什么您会从国外打到这儿来
if you're in another country,but if you'd like,
但如果您同意
I can patch you throughto the sheriff's department.
我可以为您转接本地治安部门
You don't understand. Forget it.
你没明白这是怎么回事，算了吧
Okay, okay, okay. Okay. Okay.
好的，冷静，冷静，冷静
Pick up, pick up, pick up.
快接，快接，快接
Pick up.
快接电话
Thanks for calling the Conroys.We're not home right now.
感谢致电康罗伊家，我们现在不在家
Please leave a message after the beep.Thanks!
请在听到“哔”声后留言，谢谢
Yeah, Linda. Linda, honey, it's me.
琳达，琳达，亲爱的，是我
I need you... I need you... I need youto contact the National Guard right away,
我需要你…我需要你…我需要你马上联系国民警卫队
or the Pentagon.
或者联系五角大楼
Tell them that we were attackedin the Diyala province, in Baqubah.
告诉他们我们在迪亚拉省的巴古拜遭到袭击
They need to find me. Okay?
他们必须来救我，知道了吗？
Please, baby,you've got to help them find me.
宝贝，你一定要帮他们找到我
- Hi, this is Linda.- No!
- 你好，这里是琳达- 不！
Please leave a message.Thanks and have a great day.
请留下口信，祝你生活愉快
Linda! Linda,I need you to call me right away, okay?
琳达，琳达我要你马上打电话给我，知道吗？
Call me at this number.It's an absolute emergency.
直接打这个号码，十万火急
Call me at the number that comes upon your screen right away. Okay?
打你屏幕上显示的那个号码，知道吗？
I don't know what the hell is going on,but...
我不知道到底发生了什么事，但是…
...I'm buried in a box.
…我现在被埋在一个箱子里
I'm buried in a box.
我被埋在一个箱子里
I can't breathe in here.
我快没法呼吸了
Call me whenever you can. Please, baby.
一定要马上打电话给我，宝贝
What city and state, please?
请问需要接哪个州的哪个城市？
I don't know. The FBI, wherever they are.
随便哪个，只要是FBI就行
Do you have a specific cityyou'd like to be connected to?
您需要联系指定的城市吗？
Anywhere. Any city.Just connect me to the FBI.
随便哪个城市，我只需要联系FBI
Sir, I have FBI field offices listed in Boston,Chicago, New York, Philadelphia...
先生，我可以为您转接FBI的城市有波士顿、芝加哥、纽约、费城…
- It doesn't matter.- New Haven...
- 无所谓- 纽黑文…
Any city, anywhere.Just connect me, please.
随便哪个城市，帮我转接就行了，拜托
I'm sorry, sir, but I'm not allowed to do that.
抱歉，先生，我们不允许那样做
- Chicago! Fine? Chicago! Okay?- There's no need to be rude, sir.
- 芝加哥！这下行了？芝加哥！行了吧？- 没必要这么生气，先生
Please, hold for your number.
请稍候
The number you requested...
您查询的号码是…
3-1-2
4-2-1
6-7-0-0
can be connectedfor an additional charge of 25 cents
额外支付25美分，可以直拨此号码
by pressing the number 1.
请按1键
Chicago field office. Special Agent Harris.
芝加哥办事处，特工哈里斯
- Is this the FBI?- Yes, it is, sir.
- 是FBI吗？- 是的，先生
Okay. I'm calling from Iraq.
我正从伊拉克打来的
I'm buried in the desert somewhere.I need you to help me.
我被人埋在沙漠里的某个地方我需要你救我
Whoa. Whoa. Sir, slow down.
呃，先生，请慢点说
- When were you in Iraq?- Now.
- 你什么时候在伊拉克？- 现在
Now. I'm there now. I'm a truck driver.
现在我就在这，我是一个卡车司机
I work for CRT.I've been here for nine months.
我为CRT公司工作，我来这里有九个月了
- May I have your name, please, sir?- It's Paul Conroy.
- 请问你的名字？- 我叫保罗・康罗伊
- Paul Conroy.- Yeah.
- 保罗・康罗伊- 对
Okay, Paul, explain to me what's going on.
好的，保罗，说说发生了什么事
All right, all right. Okay.
好的，好的
All right, me and a convoy of other drivers
我和车队里的其他司机
were delivering some kitchen suppliesto a community center.
正为一个社区中心运送厨具
And then some kids,they started throwing rocks at the trucks.
途中遇到一些小孩，他们开始朝卡车扔石头
And then, an IED went off up aheadand it blew up one of the other trucks.
突然前面一个简易爆炸装置爆炸了炸毁了车队的一辆卡车
And then these guys,they came out from behind the houses
紧接着一些人从房屋后面跑了出来
and they started shooting everyoneright there on the street.
他们就站在街上朝所有人扫射
- Were you shot at?- I don't know.
- 你被击中了吗？- 我不知道
I don't know.I was way in the back of the convoy.
我不知道，我在车队的末尾
I guess I got hit in the headby one of the other...
我应该是被人砸中了脑袋
By one of the rocks and I blacked out,and that's the last thing that I remember.
石头把我砸昏了接下来我就什么也不知道了
And then I woke up here, tied up,in a coffin.
我醒过来时就被绑在这个棺材里了
- Who put you there?- I guess whoever ambushed us.
- 谁把你关在里面的？- 应该是伏击我们的人
- A bunch of kids?- No. No, no, no, no, no.
- 那群小孩？- 不，不，不
Some kids, the kids,they threw the rocks at us.
那些孩子是朝我们扔石头
These guys, some Iraqis, some insurgents.I don't fucking know.
是另外的那群人他妈的不知道是伊拉克人还是反叛分子
They just... They popped outand they started shooting everybody
反正他们一跑出来就开始扫射
- rght there on the street.- I thought you said they didn't shoot at you.
- 就站在大街上- 我想你说过他们没有朝你开枪
They didn't! I don't know. They shot them!
是没有！我也不知道到底有没有反正他们杀了那些人！
Sir, you're gonna have to stop shouting.
先生，请你不要大喊大叫
I'm shoutingbecause you're not listening to me!
我大喊大叫是因为你根本没用心听我说！
I need you to help me!
我需要你来救我！
Okay. Okay, okay. I got it.
好吧，好吧，好吧，我明白了
Can you trace the call? GPS or something?
你能通过GPS或者其他方式追踪这个电话吗？
Why is it that they didn't shoot you?
为什么他们没杀你？
I don't know. I have no idea. They didn't.That's all I know.
我不知道为什么，我只知道他们没有
What's your social security number, Paul?
保罗，你的社保号是多少？
Why?
干嘛？
Why? Who cares?
谁还关心我的社保号？
I'm buried in the middleof the fucking desert,
我被埋在他妈的沙漠里
who careswhat my social security number is?
谁在乎我的社保号是多少？
I'm an American citizen.Just send someone to find me. Please!
我是美国公民，请派人来救我！
Do you have any idea where...
你知不知道你在哪…
What? Hold on, hold on. I can't hear you.
什么？别挂，别挂，我听不清
What did you... Hold on, hold on.No, no, no. I can't...
你刚才说…别挂，别挂不，不，不，我听不…
Shit!
妈的！
Fuck.
操
Come on.
快接啊
Thank you for callingCrestin, Roland and Thomas.
感谢致电CRT公司
How may I direct your call?
请问您要转接给谁？
Somebody.I need to talk to somebody right away.
随便，我要立马找个人谈话
- It's an emergency.- Who is this, please?
- 这是紧急情况- 请问您叫什么？
It's Paul Conroy.
保罗・康罗伊
I'm a driver for you guys.I'm calling from Iraq.
我是你们公司的一个司机我是从伊拉克打来的
- My convoy was attacked.- Sir, if this is a crisis situation,
- 我的车队遭到了袭击- 先生，如果情势危急
you need to contactthe safety number you were...
您应该联系发给你的安全号码…
I know. I know. I know.
我知道，我知道
I don't have it anymore. The people took it.
我的号码被人拿走了
Who took it, sir?
先生，被谁拿走了？
I don't... I don't know. The Iraqis, I think.I blacked out.
我不知道，应该是伊拉克人，我昏过去了
I'm going to put you throughto Alan Davenport.
我为您转接到艾伦・达文波特
- Who's that?- Director of personnel. Please hold.
- 他是谁？- 人事部经理，请稍候
Personnel? No, no, no, no! Wait, wait, wait!
人事部？不，不，不！等等！
At CRT, we work with our clients to provideeffective and sustainable solutions
在CRT，我们致力于为客户提供有效稳健的解决方案
to the challenges they facein our fast-growing, global economy.
帮助他们从容应对高速增长的全球化经济
As the...
作为…
You've reached Alan Davenport,
这里是艾伦・达文波特
Personnel Directorat Crestin, Roland and Thomas.
CRT公司的人事部经理
Please leave your nameand number at the tone,
请听到提示音后留下你的姓名和电话
and I will return your callas soon as possible.
我会尽快回电
This is Paul Conroy.I'm from Hastings, Michigan.
我是保罗・康罗伊，来自密歇根州黑斯廷斯
I'm a driver for CRT.
我是CRT公司的司机
My convoy was ambushed by terrorists,or insurgents. I don't know.
我的车队遭到恐怖组织或是反叛分子的伏击
I don't know who it was. And I'm stuck.
我不知道他们到底是谁反正我现在被困住了
I'm buried in a coffin in the ground,and I need help.
我被埋在一个棺材里，我需要帮助
Please send help. I m begging you.
求你派人过来救我
I think I'm in Baqubahin the Diyala province.
我想我应该位于迪亚拉省的巴古拜
I m not sure. Please.Please send help right away.
但不确定，请尽快派人来救我
I can't breathe in here. I can't breathe.
我快要不能呼吸了
I didnt know who else to call.Please, send...
我不知道还能打给谁，求你派人…
Fuck! Fuck!
操！操！
Fuck!
操！
Come on.
快点接啊
Hello? Is anybody there?
喂？有人在吗？
Hello?
喂？
- Hello?- Breathe no breathe, American?
- 喂？- 呼吸不呼吸，美国人？
- Breathe no breathe?- Wait, wait. Hold... Hold on.
- 呼吸不呼吸？- 等等，别挂
I don't know what you're saying.Who is this?
我不知道你在说什么，你是谁？
American can breathe no breathe?
美国人能不能呼吸？
No, I can't breathe.Please get me out of here.
我没法呼吸了，请放我出去吧
- Get out?- Yeah, yeah. Get me out.
- 放你出来？- 是的，放我出去
Get me out. Please help.
放我出去，求求你
- Soldier.- No, no. I'm not a soldier.
- 士兵- 不，不，我不是士兵
I'm a truck driver. Just a contractor.
我是一个卡车司机，只是一个合同工
- Contractor?- Yeah, yeah, a contractor.
- 合同工？- 对，对，合同工
That's all. No soldier.
就是这样，我不是士兵
- Blackwater.- No. Not for Blackwater.
- 黑水公司（美国著名雇佣兵和保安公司）- 不，不是为黑水公司工作
I'm not a security contractor.I'm just a truck driver. That's all.
我不是保安公司的员工我只是一个卡车司机，仅此而已
- You American?- Yeah.
- 你是美国人？- 是的
Then you soldier.
那你就是士兵
No, I'm not.
不，我不是
I'm here, unarmed. But you still shot at us.
我们手无寸铁，但你们仍朝我们开枪
In head and in throat,so you tell no more lies.
武器就在你们的头和喉咙里，别再说谎了
No, I'm not lying. We were all drivers.
我没说谎，我们都只是司机
- Drive what?- Trucks. Trucks.
- 什么司机？- 卡车，卡车司机
The trucks you see driving aroundwith supplies.
就是你们看到的那些载补给品的卡车
That's me. That's us. That's all.Not a soldier. Truck driver.
就是这样，没有士兵，都是卡车司机
- Five million, money.- What?
- 五百万，钱- 什么？
Five million, money, tonight, 9:00 p.m.,or you stay. Buried like dog.
五百万，今晚9点否则你就会像条狗一样埋着等死
- $5 million? From who?- Your family.
- 五百万美元？我哪来那么多钱？- 向你家里人要
My family doesn't have $5 million.If they did, I wouldn't be here.
我家根本没有五百万要不然我也不会到这儿来了
From embassy.
向大使馆要
I don't know. Yeah, yeah, from the embassy.
我没听懂，哦，哦，向大使馆要
If you let me out of here,they'll pay you the money. Yeah.
如果你放我出去，他们会给你们钱的
9:00 p.m., five million, money.
晚上9点，五百万
Oh God. What's your number?
天啊，号码是多少啊
- What city and listing, please?- Hastings, Michigan.
- 请问要转接的城市和明细？- 密歇根州黑斯廷斯
I'm looking for Donna Mitchell.
我找唐娜・米切尔
I have two Donna Mitchells, sir.
先生，有两个唐娜・米切尔
One on Federal Roadand one on Ardmore Avenue.
一个在联邦路，一个在阿德莫尔大道
Ardmore Avenue. I think. No. Shit!
我想是阿德莫尔大道那个吧，哦不
I don't know. Yeah, just give me that one.
我不知道，就帮我接那个吧
- Ardmore Avenue?- Yes, Ardmore Avenue.
- 阿德莫尔大道？- 对，阿德莫尔大道
Please hold for your number.
请稍候
The number you requested...
您查询的号码是
269-148
1998 can be...
1998，如需…
Come on.
快接啊
Where is everybody?
人都去哪了
- Hello?- Donna, it's Paul.
- 喂？- 唐娜，我是保罗
- Hey. How's it going?- Okay.
- 嘿，最近好吗？- 还好
I need to talk to Linda.She's not answering her phone.
我有事要找琳达，她不接我电话
I've got a problem.
我遇到麻烦了
I've been held hostageby a group of guys that...
我被一群人扣为人质…
Fooled you. I'm not really home.
骗你呢，我现在不在家
But if you leave a message, I'll get backto you as soon as I get in. Bye-bye.
如果你留下口信，我会尽快回复的，拜拜
Donna, I need to talk to Linda.It's an absolute emergency.
唐娜，我有事要找琳达，十万火急
Have her call me. Use star 69to find out the number of this phone
让她打给我用星号加69键可以查到我的号码
and have her call me at this number, okay?
就让她打这个号码，知道了吗？
- Paul?- Donna.
- 保罗？- 唐娜
- What do you want?- I need to talk to Linda. Where is she?
- 你有什么事？- 我找琳达，知道她在哪吗？
I don't know. I haven't talked to her all day.Call her cell...
我不知道，这些天都没联系她你可以打她的手机…
- Are you at your computer right now?- Yeah. Why?
- 你现在在用电脑吗？- 对，有什么事？
Okay, I need you to look up a numberfor me to the State Department.
我想让你帮忙查一下国务院的电话
Paul, I was just heading outto the supermarket. I really...
保罗，我正赶着去超市，我真的…
Please, please, please.Just look up the number for me.
拜托，拜托，拜托，帮我查一下就好
- Is everything all right?- No! Everything is not all right!
- 你还好吧？- 不！太不好了！
- Just look up the number for me.- Don't fucking yell at me...
- 快帮我查号码- 别他妈的吼我
- I'm not yelling at you, Donna.- Yes, you are.
- 我没吼你，唐娜- 你就是在吼我
No, I'm notJust get me the fucking number!
不，我没有，他妈的快给我查号码！
Get me the number!Get me the fucking number!
快查号码！快查他妈的号码！
Fuck!
操！
You stupid fucking cunt!
他妈的臭婊子！
Fuck!
操！
Fuck you, bitch! Fuck you!
操！婊子！
Fuck you!
操！
- What?- Donna, I'm very sorry that I yelled at you.
- 干嘛？- 唐娜，我为刚才的事向你道歉
I shouldn't have done that.
我不应该对你吼
But I'm only going to ask youone more time to get me this number,
我再次求你帮我查一下号码
and if you don't, I m gonna die.
如果你不帮我，我就死定了
- What?- Please, I don't have time to explain.
- 怎么了？- 求你了，我没时间解释了
- The number.- Okay, hold on.
- 我只要那个号码- 好吧，你等一下
- Okay. State Department.- Yeah.
- 我在查了，国务院- 对
- It's 202...- 202.
- 号码是202…- 202
- 134...- 134.
- 134…- 134
- 4750.- 4750?
- 4750？- 4750
- Yeah.- Okay. Fuck you.
- 对- 行了，草泥马
United States Department of State.
美国国务院
I'm an American ctizen, working in Iraq.I've been taken hostage.
我是美国公民，在伊拉克工作我被劫持为人质
- I need to speak to someone right away.- Where are you calling from, sir?
- 快给我连线管这方面的人- 先生，您从哪打来？
From Iraq. I'm a truck driver.
伊拉克，我是卡车司机
I work for CRT.Crestin, Roland and Thomas.
在CRT公司工作全称是克里斯汀、罗兰和托马斯公司
My convoy was attackedand I'm being held for ransom.
我的车队遇到袭击我现在被关押来交换赎金
- Are the kidnappers with you?- No. I m buried somewhere.
- 那些绑匪和您在一起吗？- 不，我现在被活埋了
- You're buried?- Yeah. Yeah, in a coffin.
- 您被活埋了？- 对，埋在一个棺材里
It's a wooden box, an old wooden coffin.
一个木制的老式棺材
Did you try contactingthe military out there?
您尝试过联系附近的军队了吗？
They gave me a number to call,a safety number.
他们之前给了我一个安全号码
- But the people took it.- The people holding you hostage?
- 但那些人把它拿走了- 那些劫持您的人？
- Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.- I don't know.
- 是的- 我也不知道怎么处理
- Hold on. Let me connect you...- No, don t put me on hold! No!
- 请稍候，我帮您转接到…- 别，别又让我等！不要！
- Rebecca Browning.- Hello?
- 丽贝・卡布朗宁- 接上了？
Yes, hello.I was just informed of your situation.
对，接上了，我刚被告知你的情况
Yeah, my situation.
还说我的情况
I'm running out of timeand you guys keep putting me on hold.
我时间紧迫，你那边的人还一直让我等
- What the hell is wrong with you?- I'm sorry.
- 你们怎么回事？- 抱歉
Don't be sorry. Just help me.
别道歉，快来救我
I just have a few questions for you,Mr. Conroy.
我要先问你几个问题，康罗伊先生
- You've got to be kidding me.- It's important that I get this information.
- 你开什么玩笑- 这些信息非常重要
- It'll help make a rescue attempt...- Wait, wait. Hold on, hold on. Wait, wait.
- 它们对救助行动有帮助…- 等等，等等
- How do you know my name?- I'm sorry?
- 你怎么知道我的名字？- 你说什么？
My name, I didn't give it to you.I didn't give it to the other guy either.
我的名字，我没告诉过你也没对你那边的人说过
What's going on right now?
发生了什么事？
We received a call from a representativeat CRT. You left him a message?
我们收到了CRT公司代表的来电你给他留了口信是吗？
- Yeah?- He contacted us right away.
- 对，然后呢？- 他马上联系了我们
So if you know what the hell is going on,
既然你知道这是怎么回事
then what have you doneto get me out of here?
你打算怎么来救我出去？
Well, there's little we can dofrom Washington.
我们在华盛顿也不能做什么
So that's it?I'm just supposed to sit here and rot
这就完了？那我只能在这等死？
because there's ittle you can do?
因为你们也不能做什么？
- No.- Then what?
- 我不是这个意思- 那你是什么意思？
I need to know where you werewhen your convoy was ambushed.
我要知道你的车队是在哪里遭到伏击的
- In Baqubah, in the Diyala province.- Okay.
- 在迪亚拉省的巴古拜- 好的
And has contact been madewith the kidnappers?
你现在和绑匪联系上了吗？
Yeah. The guy says he wants $5 millionby 9:00 tonight.
联系上了那人说今晚九点必须交出五百万美元赎金
Okay, or else...
否则？
Or else he'll take me to SeaWorld.
否则他们就要送我上西天
- What the hell do you think, lady?- We'll do everything we can.
- 小姐，问这么多你到底想干嘛？- 我们会尽力帮你
So you'll pay them then? Yeah?
那你们会交赎金，对吗？
- No. That we can't do.- Wait, wait. Why?
- 不，我们不会交- 等等，为什么？
It's the policyof the United States government
这是美国政府的政策
to not negotiate with terrorists.
不与恐怖分子谈判
Not the policyof the United States government?
这不符合美国政府的政策？
Lady, come on!
小姐，拜托！
You're sittng in an air conditioned office,this is easy for you to say.
你坐在开着空调的办公室里真是站着说话不腰疼
You're not the one stuck in a coffin,buried in the goddamn desert!
反正他妈的被困在棺材里埋在沙漠里的人不是你！
- I understand your frustration...- Frustration?
- 我能理解你的挫败感- 挫败？
Lady, I'm going to fucking die in here.Understand that?
小姐，我他妈的要死在这儿了这点你能理解吗？
- Hello?- I'm here.
- 喂？- 我还在这
Then say something.Tell me how you can get me out of here.
说点什么吧，告诉我你们打算怎么救我出去
Okay.
好的
What's the number on the phonethat you're calling from?
你那边的手机号码是多少？
I don't know. Did it come up on your end?
我不知道，你那边没显示吗？
No. It's listed as unavailable.
没有，我这边显示无法获取
Tell me this, can you remember a number?
那你现在能记下号码吗？
Yeah. No. I have a... I have a pencil.
可以，我这儿有一支铅笔
- Okay, write this down.- Okay, just a sec.
- 好的，你记下这个号码- 好，你等等
Okay. Go ahead.
行了，说吧
- 410...- Yeah.
- 410…- 嗯
...195...
…195…
- 5453.- 5453.
- 5453- 5453
- Who's that?- That's Dan Brenner.
- 这是谁的号码？- 丹・布伦纳
He's the commanderof the hostage working group over in Iraq.
他是伊拉克人质救援小组的指挥官
Hostage working group?
人质救援小组？
Formed it in 2004 to dealwith situations such as yours.
它成立于2004年，专门解决像你种情况
Situations.I love how you keep calling it that.
“情况”，我真喜欢你们这种叫法
- Did you write down the number?- Yeah.
- 你记下号码了吗？- 记下了
Good. Now, just hold on,I'll connect you with him now.
好的，你等一下，我现在帮你转接给他
- He should be expecting you.- What about the news? I wanna call them.
- 他应该在等你电话呢- 新闻媒体呢？我想打电话给他们
No, don't call the news.
别打给媒体
- I repeat, do not contact the news.- Why?
- 我再重复一遍，不要联系媒体- 为什么？
- It will only complicate things further...- That's bullshit.
- 这只会使事态复杂化- 胡说八道
- You're just covering your own ass.- No, I'm covering yours.
- 你们只想为自己遮丑- 不，我们是为了你好
You don't go looking for somethingyou don't know is missing.
不知道东西丢了，你就永远不会去找
Everyone who needs to know aboutthis does.
人们都应该知道这个道理
- I need all the help I can get.- We are running out of time, Paul.
- 我要尽我所能地寻求帮助- 我们的时间不多了，保罗
That's why you needto contact Dan Brenner right away.
所以你要马上联系丹・布伦纳
Fine.
好吧
I'm transferring you now.
我现在帮你转接给他
- Brenner.- Dan Brenner?
- 布伦纳- 丹・布伦纳？
- Is this Paul Conroy?- Yeah, yeah, it's me. It's Paul.
- 是保罗・康罗伊吗？- 对，就是我，我就是保罗
Paul, I was informed of what's going on.
保罗，我已经知道你的情况了
I want you to knowthat we're already working
我想让你知道
- on trying to get you out of there.- Thank you, God.
- 我们已经开始对你的救援工作了- 谢天谢地
I was told that we have until 9:00 p.m.Is that right?
我被告知的最后期限是今晚九点是这个时间吗？
- That's what he said.- All right.
- 他们就是这么说的- 好的
That doesn't give us a whole lot of time.
剩下的时间不多了
And just so I have this right,the kidnappers buried you in the ground?
我再确认一下，那些绑匪把你活埋了？
Yeah. It's an old, wooden coffin.
没错，是一个老式的木制棺材
Okay, my guess is thatsince you're able to get a cell signal,
好的，因为你还能接收到手机信号
you're no more thana few feet underground.
我想你被埋的深度大概只有几英尺
- Yeah, I don't know. Maybe.- What about battery life?
- 我也不知道，可能吧- 你的手机电量还剩多少？
- How much does the phone have left?- It's just less than half.
- 你还能用多久手机？- 还剩不到一半了
Okay, you have to conserve that battery.
好的，那你一定要节约点用
Our best bet of finding youis by tracking your cell signal.
我们找你的最佳选择就是追踪手机信号
- Is the ringer set on a sound or vibrate?- Vibrate.
- 声音模式是响铃还是震动？- 震动
I need you to pressand hold down the asterisk key
你长按星号键把它切换成响铃模式
to change it to a ring tone.It will use less power.
这样比较省电
- What about my Zippo?- You have a lighter?
- 我的Zippo打火机能做点什么？- 你有个打火机？
- Yeah.- Use it to look around for markings,
- 对- 用它检查一下四周有没有什么记号
- a logo, whatever you can find.- Won't it use up oxygen?
- 有没有标志之类的东西，尽量找找- 这会不会耗尽氧气？
Don't worry about that now.Just try to find...
别担心这个，先试着找找
- It's just so dark in here without it.- I understand, Paul.
- 但不用的话这里面太黑了- 我明白，保罗
Try to find anything in there that mightindicate where that coffin was made.
试着找找那些能显示棺材产地的标志
- You guys have to hurry.- We're working as fast as we can, Paul.
- 你们行动一定要快啊- 我们已经尽力了，保罗
Do you know if there wereany other survivors?
你知道还有没有别的幸存者吗？
- From your convoy?- Yeah.
- 你车队里的人？- 对
Still unclear at this point.
目前还不清楚
I just wanted to do right by my family.That's all.
我来这儿只是想让我家人过上好日子
I didn't know it was going to belike this out here.
但没料到会遇到这种事
I don't think any of us did.
我们谁也不会料到
- That's him. He's calling.- The kidnapper?
- 那人打电话来了- 绑匪？
- Yeah. What should I do?- You know his number?
- 对，我该怎么做？- 你知道他的号码？
- Yeah.- Give it to me.
- 对- 把号码给我
- Okay. What about the call?- Give me the number first.
- 好的，那这电话怎么办？- 先给我号码
- He's going to hang up.- Take the call.
- 他就要挂电话了- 接电话
- I... Okay.- That's okay, just take the call.
- 我…- 没关系，快接电话
Hello! Hello.
喂，喂
Two hour, four minute.
两个小时，四分钟
- You have to give me more time.- You talk to embassy?
- 你要多给我点时间- 你通知大使馆了吗？
- Give the money?- Yeah, yeah. I talked to someone.
- 交不交赎金？- 是的，我和政府的人说了
The government.They said that they won't pay the money.
他们说他们不会付钱的
- No pay?- No.
- 不付钱？- 不付
They said they don't negotiatewith terrorists.
他们说他们不和恐怖分子谈判
- Terrorists? I am terrorist?- Yeah.
- 恐怖分子？我是恐怖分子？- 是的
- Yeah. You're a terrorist, you son of a bitch.- You terrified, so I am terrorist?
- 你就是个恐怖分子，你这狗娘养的- 你害怕了，我就成恐怖分子了？
What did I ever do to you?
我做过什么伤害你的事了吗？
- Ever do?- Yeah.
- 你曾经做过的？- 是的
Yeah. I'm here because it's a job,to make money.
我到这儿来只是为了工作，我只想挣点钱
- That's it.- I have job until you come.
- 仅此而已- 我之前有工作。你来了我就失业了
- Now my family have nothing.- That's not my fault!
- 现在我家已经一无所有了- 这不是我的错
9/11 was not my fault, but you still here.
911事件也不是我的错，但你们还是来了
Saddam was not my fault, but you still here.
萨达姆也不是我的错，但你们还是来了
I told you, I'm only here to work.To help rebuild.
我说了，我到这儿来只是为了工作来帮助重建
Rebuild what you destroyed.
重建你们摧毁的东西
Stop! Stop! Just please, stop!I'm just a guy. I'm just a truck driver. Okay?
停下，停下！求你别说了！我只是一个普通人，一个卡车司机，明白吗？
I m nobody that makesdecisions about anything.
我不是决策者，只是个普通人
I just want to go home.
我只想回家
Hello?
喂？
- You make video. Ransom video.- Yeah, yeah!
- 你拍一个勒索赎金的视频- 好的，好的
I'll make a video.If you let me go, I'll make a video.
我会拍视频的，你放我出去，我会拍视频的
No. You make video now.
不行，你现在就拍
- What? How?- Use video on phone.
- 什么？现在怎么拍？- 用手机摄像头
Near foot. You read note near foot in box.
在你的脚边，读你脚边那个盒子里的纸条
- I don't see it.- Near foot.
- 我没看到盒子- 在你脚边
- Read note inside box.- Okay, okay.
- 读那个盒子里的纸条- 好的，好的
If I make the video, you let me go?
如果我拍了视频，你就会放我出去？
Only if we get money.
拿不到钱一切免谈
Nobody's going to pay $5 million for me.
没人肯为我付五百万美元
We take less. One million, money.
那就少点，一百万
If they pay, you'll let me go?
如果他们付钱，你就放我出去？
One million, money.
一百万
Thanks for calling the Conroys.We're not home right now.
感谢致电康罗伊家，我们现在不在家
Please leave a message after the beep.Thanks!
请在听到“哔”声后留言，谢谢
We're sorry, your call cannot be completed.Please, dial again.
很抱歉，您的电话未能拨通，请重拨
Shit.
操
- Paul?- Here's his number.
- 保罗？- 你记下他的号码
- Hold on. All right, go ahead.- Okay. Hold on.
- 稍候，行了，继续- 等等
It's 07-902-24-921.
号码是07-902-24-921
Okay. This is huge, Paul.Unless they're using a cloned line,
好的，这很重要，保罗只要他们用的不是克隆线路
we should be able to findwhere this is coming from in minutes.
我们几分钟内就能查出他们的位置
Okay. What about me?Can you track my cell signal?
那我这边呢？你们能追踪到我的手机信号吗？
We're having a lot of trouble with yours.
我们追踪你的信号时遇到很多麻烦
Seems to be an EDS line,
好像用的是EDS（著名IT服务公司）线路
probably throughone of the Egyptian carriers.
可能由某个埃及运营商中转
What does that mean?
什么意思？
- That it's just not going to be easy.- He wants me to make a ransom video.
- 就是说要追踪你的信号不太容易- 他让我拍一个勒索视频
No. Hold off for as long as you can.
别拍，尽量拖延时间
If it gets me out of here, I'm making it.
如果这样做能让我出去，我会拍的
The last thing we want is for thisto end up all overAI Jazeera.
我们最应该避免的就是这个视频播遍半岛电视台
- We?- Yes.
- 我们？- 是的
This can't turn intoan international incident.
不能让这件事成为国际事件
That's all you people care about, isn't it?Don't you care about me?
这才是你们这些人最关心的，不是吗？你们有没有为我想过？
- We do.- What about me?
- 当然有- 关心过我什么？
We do, Paul, we do. That's why we're here.
我们当然为你想过，保罗所以我们救你来了
No, no, no, you don't!You don't care about me.
不，不，不，你们没有！你们根本没为我考虑
You don't care about any of us.I've had eight friends
你们不关心我们任何人我有八个朋友在外面被杀害
killed out here, six of them today.
有六个就是今天被杀的
- Listen, Paul. You just...- We don't have any guns, any armor.
- 听我说，保罗，你…- 我们没有枪，也没有防护
- Nothing.- That's because you're not soldiers.
- 什么都没有- 这是因为你们不是士兵
Tell that to the peoplewho put me in this box!
这些话你和绑架我的人说去
Paul, listen.
保罗，听我说
Tell that to the people who shot my friends!
去和那些杀我朋友的人说去！
- We're doing the best we can.- No, you're not! You're not!
- 我们正在尽全力救你- 不，你们没有，你们没有！
- Okay, calm down.- I've been out here nine months.
- 你冷静点- 我来这已经九个月了
I know how it works.All you guys care about
我知道你们所谓的救援
is your secret plansand your back-room politics.
你们这些人只关心你们的秘密计划和你们那些见不得光的政治
You know, if I was a diplomat,
我跟你说，如果我是外交官
or a hostage working group leader,or what the fuck your title is,
或者人质救援小组的指挥或者别的他妈的你这样的头衔
I'd be out of here by now.
我早就已经获救了
But I'm notso I'm just supposed to sit in here,
可惜我不是，所以我只能在这里闭上嘴等死
- shut my mouth and die.- Okay, I need you to stay focused, Paul.
我需要你集中注意力，保罗
Fuck you, Dan.
去你他妈的，丹
Paul, listen to me.Finding you is our primary concern.
保罗，听我说，找到你是我们的首要责任
Bottom line. And we're searching for you
我们也正在尽全力找你
just as hard as we would befor a four-star general,
就像搜救四星上将般努力
so don't literally waste your breathsuggesting otherwise.
所以不要浪费氧气来争论了
I can't... I can't....
我不能…我不能
Are you injured, Paul? Are you okay?
你受伤了吗，保罗？你还好吧？
I don't know. Who are they?
我不知道，那些人是谁？
The people who put me in here,who are they?
那些把我弄进来的人是谁？
They're just that, people.
他们仅仅是人
- No different from you and me.- I'm not a terrorist.
- 和你我没有什么区别- 我不是恐怖分子
- Neither are they.- How do you know?
- 他们也不是- 你怎么知道？
If you were homeless, starving...Actually, I take that back.
如果你无家可归、忍饥挨饿…我换一个方式表达
If your family was homeless and starving,what would you do for them?
如果你的家人无家可归、忍饥挨饿你会为他们做什么？
- I wouldn't kill somebody.- How can you be sure?
- 那我也不会去杀人- 你又怎么能肯定呢？
What difference does it make?
那你说这样的话又有什么用？
They're criminals, desperate ones at that.
这群人就是这种走入绝境的罪犯
They don't care about anythingother than getting the money.
他们除了钱，什么都不在乎
So pay them, just pay them.
那就给他们钱，交赎金啊
Trust me, if it was an option,I would do that in a heartbeat.
相信我，如果有选择的话我立马就会给钱的
How many others have there been?
以前有多少人像我这样被绑架？
- Since I got here?- Yeah.
- 从我到这工作以来？- 对
Dozens. Journalists, contractors, soldiers.
好几十个，有记者、合同工、士兵
Dozens have been taken. It's one ofthe only functioning businesses out here.
一共有几十个绑架是这里仅存的几种交易之一了
How many have you rescued?
那你们救出过多少人？
- How many?- Not many.
- 多少人？- 不多
- Tell me their names.- No.
- 告诉我他们的名字- 不行
- Any of them.- Who?
- 随便说个人- 说谁？
Make me believethat they really do matter to you.
至少让我相信你们真的在乎他们
That they really do matter to you.
真的在乎他们的生死
- Mark White.- Who was Mark White?
- 马克・怀特- 他是谁？
A kid from New Hampshire.Twenty-six years old. Med student.
他是新罕布夏州医学院的学生，二十六岁
Came over here to help out local doctors.
来这里帮助当地的医生
What happened to him?
他发生了什么事？
- Insurgents grabbed him.- When?
- 他被叛军挟持了- 什么时候？
About three weeks ago.
大概三个星期之前
- You remember his name?- I remember all their names.
- 你还得住他的名字？- 我记得所有人的名字
Is he... Did he?
那他…他还…
Yeah. Yeah, he's alive.
对，他还活着
- Where is he now?- Home.
- 他现在在哪？- 在家里
Probably happy to be back at school.
说不定在为返校高兴呢
I want to get out of here.
我想从这出去
We found him. We'll find you, too.
我们能找到他，同样也能找到你
How?
怎么找？
We already have a solid leadon the number you gave us.
我们已经找出你给的号码的位置
- You do?- Yeah. A unit's on its way over there now.
- 真的？- 对，一队人已经赶过去了
That's good.
太好了
- That feels good.- Yeah.
- 太好了- 是的
What... What should I do in the meantime?
我现在该怎样做？
I know it's hard, but try to relax.
我知道这很困难，但你要试着放松
The more worked up you are,the more air you're going to use.
你的活动越频繁，氧气的消耗就越多
Okay, I know.
好，我知道了
I know. It's hard, 'cause I have anxiety.
这的确很困难，因为我有焦虑症
I take pills for it.
我得吃药才行
Do you have them with you?
现在你那有药吗？
- Yeah.- Good. Take them.
- 有- 很好，那就吃点药吧
You need to preserve your oxygen levelany way you can.
你要尽量维持里面的氧气水平
Okay.
好的
- Is your Zippo still lit?- No, not anymore.
- 你的打火机还点着吗？- 不，没点了
- All right. Good.- I feel nauseous.
- 那就好- 我感觉有点恶心
- You have to calm down.- Okay.
- 你一定要静下心来- 好的
And you need to save that battery.
还有要节约手机电池
We're expecting some intelin about 10 minutes.
我们估计10分钟左右会有进展
- Call me back then.- Okay.
- 到时候你再打给我- 好的
- Just hang in there, Paul.- I'm trying, okay.
- 你要坚持住，保罗- 好的，我尽力
- What?- You make video?
- 什么事？- 视频拍了吗？
- No.- You make video!
- 没有- 快拍！
- Let me out and I'll make it.- No!
- 你放我出去，我一定拍- 不行！
- You make video now.- I can't read the paper.
- 你现在就拍- 我看不清纸上的字
- Make video now!- I can't.
- 现在就拍！- 我没法拍
I don't know what you want me to say.I can't read the paper.
我看不清字，不知道你们想让我说什么
You make video! Now!
你快拍视频！现在就拍！
Fuck!
操！
Okay, okay. Come on, come on, come on.
冷静，冷静，冷静
Come on!
冷静！
Come on, come on, come on,come on, come on, come on.
冷静，冷静，冷静
Fuck.
操
Shit.
Mountain View Nursing Home.
山景疗养院
Hi. I was hoping that I could speakwith Maryanne Conroy, please.
麻烦你让玛丽安娜・康罗伊接一下电话
Okay.
好的
Let me bring the cordless phoneto her room. Hold on one moment, please.
请稍候，我把无绳电话拿到她房间去
Mrs. Conroy,you have a telephone call, dear.
康罗伊太太，有你的电话
Here, you can use this phone.
给，可以用这个接听
Hello?
喂？
Mom, it's Paul.
妈妈，我是保罗
Who?
谁？
It's Paul, your son.
你儿子保罗
I have a son?
我有儿子？
It's okay, Mom. How are you?
没关系，妈妈，你还好吗？
- I'm fine.- That's good.
- 我很好- 那就好
Who are you?
你是谁？
It's your son, Mom. It's Paulie.
我是你的儿子，妈妈，我是小保罗啊
- Paulie.- Yeah.
- 小保罗- 是的
Remember? Used to live on Colfax Street,in the duplex. You remember?
想起来了吗？还记得以前住在科法斯街的小公寓里的时候吗？
- Paulie?- Yeah.
- 小保罗？- 是啊
- That's right.- Is this Paulie?
- 就是我- 你真的是小保罗？
It is. It's Paulie.
对，我就是小保罗
- How's everything at the home?- Very nice.
- 家里一切怎么样？- 很好
Your father and I have beenplaying Gin Rummy every night.
我和你父亲每天晚上都打牌（Gin Rummy：一种纸牌游戏）
Yeah.
哦
I don't think Pop's there with you, Mom.
妈妈，我不认为爸爸和你在一起
How are you doing, sweetie?
你过得怎么样，亲爱的？
Not very good.
不太好
This might be the last timethat I talk to you.
这可能是我最后一次和你说话了
That's nice, honey.
没关系，宝贝
Did you get the flowers I sent youa few months ago?
你收到几个月前我给你寄的花了吗？
Flowers?
花？
Yeah, I sent you... Never mind.
恩，我寄给你的…不管它了
Look, I'm gonna get going now, okay?
我现在要挂电话了，好吗？
I just wanted to call and talk to you.
我只是想和你说说话
I love you, Mom.
我爱你，妈妈
I said, I love you, Mom.Do you want to tell me that you love me?
我说，我爱你，妈妈你不打算对我说你爱我吗？
Yes, dear. Your father and I have beenplaying Gin Rummy every night.
是的，亲爱的，我和你父亲每天晚上都打牌
Okay, Mom.
好吧，妈妈
You tell Pop I said hi.
代我向爸爸问好
No.
不
No, no, no, no, no!
不，不，不！
No, no, no, no, no, no!
别啊，别啊！
- Video make?- Please! Don't hurt her!
- 视频拍了吗？- 求求你，别伤害她！
- Don't hurt her! Let her go.- I shoot if you no make video.
- 别伤害她，放了她吧- 你不拍视频我就开枪
- No! No! Don't shoot her. Dont shoot.- You get money. American million.
- 别，别，别杀她，别开枪- 你拿钱来，美元
I will. I will I promise.
钱一定会给的，我保证
I promise. Please, she's a mother.She has two kids.
我保证，求你了，她是两个孩子的母亲
- Two kids?- Yes. She has two kids.
- 两个孩子？- 对，她有两个孩子
I had five. Now only one.
我有五个孩子，但现在只剩下一个了
- You make video now!- Wait! Wait!
- 你现在就拍视频！- 等等！
- No, wait!- I give three seconds.
- 等等！- 我给你三秒钟
- I don't know what you want me to say!- Three...
- 我不知道你们想让我说什么！- 三…
- Okay! Okay! I'll make the video!- Two, one!
- 好好好，我拍视频！- 二、一！
I'll make the video! I'll make the video!Please, please, please.
我拍视频，我拍视频！求你，我求你了！
I have to hang up now to make the video.Is that okay?
我现在挂断电话拍视频，行吗？
You have three minute to send video.
你有三分钟的时间把视频发过来
My name is Paul Conroy.
我叫保罗・康罗伊
I'm an American citizenfrom Hastings, Michigan.
我是美国公民，来自密歇根州黑斯廷斯
I'm a civilian truck driverfor Crestin, Roland and Thomas.
我是CRT公司的一个普通卡车司机
And I have been taken hostagesomewhere in Iraq.
我现在在伊拉克的某地被挟持作为人质
I need $1 million by 9:00 tonight,Baghdad time,
我要在巴格达时间今晚九点前交一百万美元赎金
or I'll be left to die herein this coffin that I'm buried in.
否则我就要在这个棺材里等死
I'm told that if the money is paid...
绑匪说如果付了钱…
I'm told that if the money is paid,I will be let go.
绑匪说如果付了钱就会放我走
If it is not, I will be left to die here.
如果不付钱，我就要在这等死
These threats are realand will be followed through on.
我所说的都是真实的，他们真的会撕票
Oh, my God.
天啊
I got you.
总算找到了
I got you, you motherfucker.
总算找到了，你他妈的
I got you. I got you. I got you. I got you.
找到了，找到了，找到了
Fucking A. Okay.
你他妈的
Come on, come on, come on.Pick up, pick up, pick up, pick up, pick up.
快接啊，快接啊
Hi, this is Linda. Please leave a message.
你好，我是琳达，请留下口信
Thanks and have a great day.
祝你生活愉快
Linda, I figured out the numberof the phone. I got it.
琳达，我找到这个手机的号码了
I got it.
我找到了
Okay. It's 0792-42-884.
号码是0792-42-884
Use the international calling code to dial it.I got it, baby.
加上国际区号后就可以打给我了宝贝，我总算找到它了
I love you. Call me as soon as you get this.Call me. I love you.
我爱你，尽快给我回电一定要记得回电，我爱你
Oh, shit.
完了
Shit.
Okay.
这下好了
Fuck. Come on.
快亮啊
Fuck.
操
My name is Pamela Lutti.
我叫帕梅拉・露蒂
I'm a food service worker at FOB Anaconda,
我负责为柯尔特蟒蛇（枪支名）的交易船只提供食物
employed by Crestin, Roland and Thomas.
我受雇于CRT公司
My captors'requestshave gone unanswered.
绑匪的要求没有得到答复
Please. Please, don't!
求求你，求求你，不要
My name is Pamela Lutti.
我叫帕梅拉・露蒂
Please, don't!
求求你，不要！
If you're buried in a coffin,where are you calling from?
如果您被埋在一个棺材里那您怎么给我打的电话？
The number you requested,
您查询的号码是
269-948-1998.
269-948-1998
They're criminals, desperate ones at that.
这群人就是被逼上绝路的罪犯
They don't care about anythingother than getting...
他们除了钱，什么都不在乎…
At CRT,we work with our clients to provide...
在CRT，我们致力于为客户提供…
Sir, you're gonna have to stop shouting.
先生，请你不要大喊大叫
Five million, money, tonight, 9:00 p.m.,or you stay.
五百万，钱，今晚9点，否则你就等死吧
Finding you is our primary concern.Bottom line.
我们的首要任务就是找到你
Thanks for calling the Conroys.We're not home right now.
感谢致电康罗伊家，我们现在不在家
Please, leave a message after the beep.Thanks!
请在听到“哔”声后留言，谢谢
Why the hell did you make that video?
你为什么要拍那视频？
- It's all a bunch of lies.- What is?
- 全都是骗人的- 什么？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
- All of it.- All of what?
- 统统都是- 什么统统都是？
You don't give a shit about any of us.We're nothing to you people.
你们根本不在乎我们对你们来说我们什么都不是
We're going to find you.
我们会救你出来的
Fuck off, Dan. You're babysitting.
去你妈的，丹，你想骗谁啊
Just gonna stay on the phonewith me until I die.
你只会在电话上跟我说说，直到我死掉
Okay. You can't start breakingon me now, Paul.
保罗，你现在不能放弃
- You have to stay strong.- They shot her and you didn't do anything.
- 你一定要坚强- 他们杀了她，你们却什么也没有做
We didn't even knowshe'd been taken hostage.
我们之前根本不知道她也被绑架了
- She sent three videos.- Yeah. That's what they told her to say.
- 她发了三段视频- 是的，那是他们要挟她说的
- Why?- I don't know.
- 为什么- 我不知道
What do you know?
那你知道什么？
That your ransom video alreadyhas 47,000 hits on YouTube.
他们把你的勒索视频放到了YouTube上点击率已经达到了47000
And all the major networks are playing it,including A Jazeera.
各大网站都已经转载半岛电视台也做了报道
So now your captors have no choicebut to follow through.
所以现在绑匪已经骑虎难下，只能硬来了
I found out the number to this phone.
我找到我这个手机的号码了
- How?- Who cares?
- 怎么找到的？- 这很重要吗？
I figured it out and you didn't. Why?
我把它找出来了而你没有，这是为什么？
Because I didn't.
因为我没有
Just like you and every other personon the planet,
这个星球上的所有人，包括你我在内
there are some things I know,and there are some things I don't.
总有些事是知道的，而有些事不知道
Then how am I ever gonna get out of here?
那我是不是永远也出不去了？
Their signal was cloned, like we figured.But we're close. Really close.
我之前跟你说过，他们的信号是克隆的不过我们快要找到他们了，真的快了
I'm near a mosque.
我在一个清真寺附近
I heard a call to prayer over the PA.
我听到外面的祷告声了
Good. Good.That means that we're in the right area.
很好，很好，这说明我们找对地方了
You're...
你们…
You're nearby?
你们在附近？
I spoke with soldiers from the 3rd IDwho were escorting your convoy.
我和护送你们的那队士兵谈过
They're alive?
他们还活着？
Not all of them.Both Bradley tanks were hit with IEDs.
一部分还活着有两辆布拉德利装甲车被炸弹损毁了
The rest got caught in small arms fire.
其他人遭到了轻武器的袭击
What the hell happened out there, Paul?
到底是怎么回事，保罗？
Paul?
保罗？
Wait.
等等
Paul?
保罗？
Fuck!
操
Come on. Come on.
快来信号啊
Come on. Come on. Come on.
快啊，快啊，快啊
Come on.
快啊
Hello?
喂？
- Hello, who's there?- Is this Paul Conroy?
- 喂，你是谁？- 你是保罗・康罗伊吗？
Yeah, yeah, yeah. It's Paul. Who are you?
是的，是的，我是保罗，你是谁？
Paul, my name's Alan Davenport.
保罗，我叫艾伦・达文波特
I'm the Personnel Director hereat Crestin, Roland and Thomas.
CRT公司的人事部经理
Yeah, yeah. I left you a message.
是的，我给你留了口信
You did.I also heard from Rebecca Browning
<i>over at the State Department.</i>
是的，我还从国务院的丽贝・卡布朗宁那听说了你的情况
Are you able to speakon the status of your situation?
你现在方便谈谈吗？
It's worse.There was an explosion or something,
不太方便，我这里好像发生了爆炸
and the sand's coming through.
沙子灌了进来
I probably have about half an hourbefore it fills right up.
大概半小时就会填满了
Slow down. You should try to stay calm.
别着急，你要保持冷静
So tell me something, Paul.Who have you spoken to?
保罗，说说你都和谁谈过吧
The hostage-takers, Dan Brennerfrom the hostage working group...
有绑匪、人质救援小组的丹・布伦纳…
Okay, Paul. I'm with you.Now, how about the media?
别担心，保罗，我会帮你的媒体那是怎么回事？
I know your ransom video leaked,
据我所知你的勒索视频已经泄露了
but have you spoken directly to anyoneabout what's going on?
那你和什么人直接说过这件事吗？
- No. No, no, no, no.- Good, good, good, good.
- 没有，没有- 很好，很好
It needs to stay that way.
你接下来要保持这样
It's important we keep this situationas contained as possible.
我们必须掌控局势，这至关重要
The situation is in a coffin!
现在的情况是我被关在棺材里！
I think it's pretty contained! Help me!Help me!
这局势已经不能再怎么被控制了救我，救救我！
What are you doing right now to help me?
你现在哪是在救我
I know you're upset.But from what I've been told,
我知道你很不安，但我刚才得到消息
they're extremely closeto getting you out of there.
救援人员马上快要找到你了
So hopefully, it won't be too much longer.
你很可能很快就会获救了
- Thank God.- Yeah, thank God.
- 谢天谢地- 是的，谢天谢地
Now, I'm going to switch on a recorderright now.
现在我要打开录音机了
- What?- Just a second.
- 什么？- 稍等
This is Alan Davenport,
我是艾伦・达文波特
Personnel Director atCrestin, Roland and Thomas Incorporated.
CRT公司人事部经理
The date is October 23, 2006.
今天是2006年10月23日
I'm speaking with Paul Conroy.
我正在和保罗・康罗伊谈话
Mr. Conroy, are you aware thatI'm recording this conversation?
康罗伊先生，请问你知道我正在录音吗？
- What?- Please answer the question.
- 什么？- 请回答我的问题
- Shit.- Mr. Conroy?
- 操- 康罗伊先生？
Yeah! Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
知道，知道，知道
And do I have your permission to do so?
你是否已经授权我录下谈话过程了？
Why do you need my permission?What's this about?
为什么要我的授权？这是要干嘛？
I need you to answer yes or no, please.
请回答是或不是
- Yes! Yes, all right?- Thank you.
- 是！是，行了吧？- 多谢
Now, Mr. Conroy,when were you hired by CRT?
康罗伊先生，现在我要问你你是什么时候进入CRT公司的？
I don't... Nine months ago. Around January.What is all this?
记不清…九个月前，一月份左右你到底是要干嘛？
I have your official date of hireas January 4th.
公司的记录显示是一月四号
- Is that correct?- Who cares?
- 请问这是正确的吗？- 管他是哪天
This is fucking crazy.
这真他妈的神经病
- January 4th. Is that correct?- Yes!
- 一月四号是否正确？- 是的
And during your initial training,before being sent to Iraq,
还有，在你被派往伊拉克之前的培训中
you were made aware of the dangersinherent to the position
<i>for which you were hired.</i>
你是否已经清楚认识到其中潜在的危险
You mean when I camedown there to Dallas,
你是指当我到达拉斯的时候
and you guys said that all of the trucks
你们的人告诉我们
would be armoredand have bulletproof glass?
所有卡车都配备有武器和防弹玻璃吗？
You mean when you told us that thingswere safer than ever over here?
你指的是你们告诉我们，安全万无一失吗？
Is that when... Is thatwhen I was made aware?
你是问那时候我有没有清楚认识到吗？
I need you to answer yes or no, please.
请回答是或不是
Yes.
是
During that time, did you also receiveand sign an employment contract with CRT,
在此期间，你是否收到并签署了CRT公司的雇佣合同
which thoroughlyexplained company policy
并且合同中已经详述了公司制度
as it pertained toyour specific terms of employment?
其中也包括具体的雇佣条件？
Yeah, yeah, yeah,I signed a bunch of things. Yeah.
是的，是的，我当时是签了一大堆东西
- Yes or no?- Yes! I signed the contract. Yes.
- 回答是或不是- 是！我是签了合同
It's our understandingthat you were taken hostage in Iraq
据我们了解你在两个小时前在伊拉克被绑架
two hours ago, is that also correct?
请问是否正确？
Yes! I think that's a fair assessmentof the situation, you fucking dick.
是！这个描述很符合真实情况，你他妈的
What's the point of all this?
你到底想干嘛？
Our legal department requires that
<i>we obtain a sworn affidavit from employees,</i>
公司法律部门要求我们必须取得员工的证词
confirming that theyunderstand the reasons
以确定员工明白
for their forced separationfrom the company.
公司解雇他们的原因
As of this morning, your employmentwith CRT was officially terminated.
今天上午你与CRT的工作关系已经正式解除了
Wait, wait, wait, wait,wait, wait, wait. What?
等等，等等，等等，你说什么？
It was brought to our attentionthat you were engaging
因为我们注意到你与CRT公司的同事
in relations with a fellowCRT employee, Pamela Lutti.
帕梅拉・露蒂有不寻常的关系
- No. No, no. Hold on, hold on.- Stipulated in your contract
- 不，不，不，等等，等等- 公司有员工交友的条款
was a fraternization clause,in which it was stated quite clearly
在合同里写的很清楚
- that any relationship...- Stop, stop, stop. Please.
- 员工之间…- 别再说了
... be it romantic or sexual in nature...
恋爱或者发生性关系…
- We were just friends.- ... deemed inappropriate
- 我们只是朋友关系- 都是明令禁止的
by CRT senior officlalsis grounds for immediate termination.
否则CRT公司有权立即终止合同
Hold on. Okay? We were just friends.We were just friends.
你能不能停一下？我们只是朋友仅仅是普通朋友
- Our records indicate differently.- Your records are wrong.
- 我们的记录可不是你说的那样- 你们的记录有问题
We're also legally required to inform you
按照法律，我们有义务通知你
that because you weretechnically no longer
从理论上来说
under the employ of CRTat the time of your abduction,
在你被绑架的时候你已经不属于CRT员工了
we cannot be heldaccountable for any injury
我们不会对员工在合同到期后
that may befall upon you afteryour official date and time of termination.
所受到的任何伤害负责
Therefore, in your case,that includes this incident,
因此，就你的情况而言也包括你的这次意外
or any consequencesthat may result from it.
以及因此导致的任何后果
What about my insurance money?My family's gonna need that money.
那我的保险金呢？我的家人需要那笔钱
Given that you were aliveup until the time of your termination...
只会赔付你在合同终止前的部分…
Don't do this.
别这样
- Do you understand everything?- Don't do this!
- 你是否已经清楚整个情况？- 别这样！
Do you understandeverything you've been told, Mr. Conroy?
你是否已经清楚我对你所说的情况康罗伊先生？
Mr. Conroy?
康罗伊先生？
You're a piece of shit.
你就是一坨狗屎
That concludes our interviewwith Paul Conroy.
与保罗・康罗伊的谈话到此结束
I am now turning off the recorder.
现在关闭录音
You put me here.
是你们把我派过来的
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
Answer the phone. Answer the phone.
快接电话，快接电话
Come on.Why won't you answer the phone?
快接，为什么还不接电话？
Paul, is that you?
保罗，是你吗？
They're dead.
他们死了
- How do you know that?- I just do.
- 你怎么知道？- 反正我知道
Three F-16s leveled parts of the citya few minutes ago.
三架F-16战机几分钟前轰炸了城中部分地区
Yeah, I know.
我知道
Yeah, that was fun for me.
这是个好消息
Did they know I was here?
他们知道我在这吗？
- Yeah.- Yeah.
- 知道- 好的
Did they care?
他们在乎吗？
These people that took me, if they're dead,
如果那些绑架我的人都死了
they can't tell you where I am.
就没人能告诉你们我在哪了
We can still try to track down your signal.
我们还可以追踪你的手机信号
You tried that already.
你们已经试过了
We can try again.
我们可以再试
- It's over, isn't it?- No.
- 一切都结束了，是吗？- 没有
Yeah.
是的
What should I do?
那我该怎么办？
I don't know.
我不知道
It's weird.
这真奇怪
What is?
什么东西奇怪？
Knowing.
先知的感觉
I wish this could havegone differently, Paul.
保罗，我希望事情能有所转机
Yeah.
是的
Me, too.
我也是
My name is Paul Steven Conroy.
我叫保罗・史蒂芬・康罗伊
Social security number, 048-32-1198.Date of birth, 3/23/76.
社保号码是048-32-1198出生于1976年3月23日
This video will serveas my last will and testament.
这段视频将作为我的遗嘱
To my wife, Linda Conroy,
我的妻子琳达・康罗伊
I leave you the $700 in my personal savings,
我将我的700美元个人储蓄留给你
and whatever's left in my annuity.
还有我待领的养老金
To my son, Shane Conroy,
我的儿子沙恩・康罗伊
I don't know.
我不知道能留给你什么
I don't have... My clothes.
我没什么东西…我还有些衣服
I leave you my clothes,which you will grow into.
我把我的衣服留给你，你长大后就能穿了
Not these ones.
不包括我穿的这件
I don't really have...
我真的没什么东西
I wish that I had more for you, but...
我希望我能给你留下更多，但是…
Maybe if I was a famous baseball player,or some guy who wore a suit to work...
如果我是个明星棒球手或者像那些西装革履的人
Then I'd have more.
我就会拥有更多了
But, you know, you can beone of those people if you want.
不过如果你肯努力你以后也可以成为他们中的一员
Yeah. Yeah.
真的
Just promise me that when you get olderthat you'll take good care of your mom.
答应我长大以后要好好照顾母亲
And, I don't know.
还有，我也不知道该怎么说
You always try to do the right thing.
你总是试着不做错事
I love you very much, Shane.
我很爱你，沙恩
Maybe I never said that enough.Maybe I did. I don't know.
可能我说爱你说得不够或许也有那么多，我不知道
That probably means I didn't. And...
这大概正意味着我说得不够，还有…
I'm sorry, Linda.I should have listened to you.
对不起，琳达，我当初应该听你的
You're not dead. Hello? Hello?
你们还没死，喂？喂？
Where is money?
钱在哪？
- I don't know- What don't know?
- 我不知道- 不知道什么？
- I don't know where it is.- Liar!
- 我不知道钱在哪- 你骗我
No, I'm not lying! I swear.
不，我没骗你！我发誓
- Swear?- Yeah, I swear.
- 发誓？- 是的，我发誓
- I'm telling the truth.- From embassy.
- 我说的都是真的- 向大使馆要
- No.- You get money now!
- 不- 你现在就向他们要钱！
- I cant!- You will!
- 我不能- 你会去要的
- I need more time. Please.- No more time!
- 我求你多给我点时间- 不可能
There's sand pouring in here.
沙子正在灌进来
It's everywhere. Let me out of here,and I promise you I will get you the money.
到处都是沙子，放我出去我保证你会拿到钱的
- You show blood.- What?
- 你得放点血- 什么？
- You show blood, they give money.- No.
- 你放点血，他们就会给钱了- 不
You cut finger, send video.
你切掉手指，拍视频发过来
- No, I'm not doing that.- Yes!
- 不，我不会切的- 你会的
- No.- No?
- 不- 不切？
No, that's right, no. You let me out of here,
对，我不会切的，你先放我出去
and I'll cut offmy whole goddamn hand if you want.
到时候就算他妈的整个手我都切
- You have wife?- Yeah, I do.
- 你有妻子？- 对
And a son. I have a young son.And I want to see them again. Please, sir.
还有一个儿子，我希望还能再看到他们求求你了，先生
- Sir?- Yes. Sir.
- 先生？- 是的，先生
I say that out of respect to you.
我这么称呼是出于对你的尊重
243, North Walnut Street.Hastings, Michigan, USA.
美国密歇根州黑斯廷斯北沃尔纳特街243号
That's my... Why did you say that?
这是我家…你说这些什么意思？
You show blood, or they show blood.
你放血，否则他们放血
No. You're nobody, all of you.
不，你做不到，你们都不能
You can't get to them.
你们根本找不到那儿
- No?- No.
- 找不到？- 找不到
You're peasants.You're fucking criminals, that's all.
你们都是农民，你们还都是他妈的罪犯
You don't even know where Michigan is.
你们连黑斯廷斯在哪都不会知道
Detroit. Ann Arbor.
底特律，安娜堡
You looked at a map. You looked at a map.
你在查地图，你在查地图
You show blood, or they show blood.Send video by five minutes.
你放血，否则他们放血五分钟内把视频发过来
Hi, this is Linda. Please leave a message.Thanks and have a great day.
你好，我是琳达，请留下口信，祝你生活愉快
Linda! Linda, listen to me,
琳达，琳达，听我说
you and Shane haveto go somewhere, okay?
你要赶快带沙恩找地方躲起来，知道了吗？
Do not go back to the house.Do not go back to the house.
千万不要回家，千万不要回家
Just go anywhere but to the house.
随便去哪，千万别回家
Okay?These guys, they know where we live.
知道了吗？那些人知道我们的住处
They have my driver's license.
他们有我的驾照
Just go to the sheriff's stationif you have to, just do not go home.
如果没地方去就去警察局，千万不要回家
Holy God.
天呐
Fuck.
操
This is Daniel Brenner.Please leave a message at the tone.
我是丹尼尔・布伦纳请听到提示音后留下口信
Brenner, where are you?The guy's still alive!
布伦纳，你在哪？那些人还活着！
He just called me. He's still alive.
他刚才给我打电话了，他还活着
Fuck.
操
They can't fnd them. They can't.
他们找不到那些绑匪，他们找不到
There's no way. No, no, no, no, no.
不可能，不可能
They can't fnd them. They can't find them.They can't find them.
他们找不到那些绑匪，他们找不到那些绑匪
Fuck.
操
My name is Pamela Lutti.
我叫帕梅拉・露蒂
I'm a food service worker at FOB Anaconda,
我负责为柯尔特蟒蛇（枪支名）的交易船只提供食物
employed by Crestin, Roland and Thomas.
我受雇于CRT公司
My captors'requestshave gone unanswered.
绑匪们的要求没有得到答复
Please. Please, don't!
求求你，求求你，不要
Fuck.
操
- Around to the other side!- Move it, move it, move it!
- 绕到对面去！- 快，快，快！
I see him! Move it!
我看见他了！快！
Get back! Everybody, get back!
退后！统统退后！
Civilian has been located.Civilian has been located.
被困者已经找到，被困者已经找到
Are you okay? Talk to me.
你怎么样？告诉我
Paul, are you okay?
保罗，你怎么样了？
Yeah?
喂？
Paul? Paul, it's Brenner.
保罗？保罗，我是布伦纳
- Are you there, Paul?- I'm here?
- 你在听吗，保罗？- 我在听
We're coming for you now. You hear me?We know where you are.
我们现在来救你了，你听到了吗？我们知道你在哪了
- You're coming?- We are, Paul.
- 你们救我来了？- 是的，保罗
- We're almost there now.- How do you know?
- 我们就要到了- 你怎么知道？
Coalition forces picked upa Shi'ite insurgent just outside of Baghdad.
刚刚部队在巴格达附近逮捕了一个什叶派叛乱分子
Said he knew wherean American was buried alive.
他说他知道一个被活埋的美国人在哪
He agreed to show us whereif we let him go.
只要我们答应放了他，他就会带我们去那
- You're coming for me?- We are practically there already.
- 你们救我来了吗？- 我们就要到了
- You have... You have to hurry.- We are, Paul.
- 你们一定…你们一定要尽快- 我们会尽快的，保罗
You have to hurry. The sand... The sand...
你们一定要尽快，沙子…沙子…
You just hang in there three more minutes.
你只要再坚持三分钟
This will all be over soon, I promise, Paul.
我保证这一切很快就会结束了，保罗
Okay. Okay. I believe you.
好，好，我相信你
Three minutes, Paul. I just needyou to hang on for three minutes.
三分钟，保罗，你只要再坚持三分钟
- Thank you.- This will all be over soon. I promise you...
- 谢谢你- 这一切很快就会结束了，我向你保证
- I have to go! Call me right back.- No, no, no! Paul, Paul, Paul!
- 我得挂电话了！到时候再打给我- 别挂，别挂！保罗，保罗！
- Call me right back. Please!- No, wait, Paul!
- 到时候打给我，拜托！- 别挂，等等，保罗
Linda! Linda!
琳达！琳达！
Paul? Paul, is that you?
保罗？保罗，是你吗？
- Tell me it's you.- It's me.
- 快告诉我真的是你- 是我
Oh, my God, Paul!What are they doing to you?
天啊，保罗，他们对你做了什么？
- Please tell me you're okay.- I'm okay.
- 快告诉我你没事- 我没事
I just saw the news.I left my cell phone at home.
我刚看到新闻，我把手机忘在家里了
They know where I am.They're coming to get me.
他们知道我的位置了，正赶来救我
The Americans are coming for me.
美国人正赶过来救我
- They are?- It's going to be okay.
- 真的吗？- 我很快会没事了
Thank God. Thank God.
谢天谢地，谢天谢地
They're coming. They're on their way.It's gonna be okay.
他们就要来了，已经快到了我很快就会没事了
I was so afraid I was going to lose you.
我真的好担心会失去你
- You're not.- I love you so much.
- 你不会失去我的- 我真的很爱你
- I love you so much.- I love you so much.
- 真的很爱你- 我也很爱你
I love you so much. I'm so sorry.I should never have come here.
我也很爱你，对不起我从一开始就不应该到这儿来
I should have listened to you. I'm sorry.
我应该听你的，对不起
Sweetie, I don't care. I just want you home.Please come home to me.
亲爱的，我无所谓，只要你能平安回来你一定要回到我身边
I'm coming home. I'm coming home.
我会回去的，我会回去的
- Swear it.- I swear.
- 你发誓- 我发誓
- I swear I'm coming home.- I love you. I love you so much.
- 我发誓我一定会平安回去- 我爱你，我真的很爱你
I know.
我知道
- They're here.- Okay.
- 他们打电话来了- 好的
They're here! I have to go.
他们打电话来了！我要挂了
- Call me right away.- I will. I promise you
- 待会打给我- 我会的，我保证
- I will. I love you.- I love you. Swear it.
- 我会的，我爱你- 我也爱你，我发誓
- I love you so much.- Swear it again.
- 我非常非常爱你- 再发一次誓
I swear! I have to go.
我发誓！我得挂电话了
- Please come home to me.- I love you.
- 你一定要回到我身边来- 我爱你
- Dan?- Move! Move! Let's go!
- 丹？- 快！快！快行动！
- Brenner?- Okay, Paul? Paul? We're here!
- 布伦纳？- 喂，保罗吗？我们到了
- It's me.- He brought us right to you.
- 是我- 他带我们来找你了
Hurry, hurry. You have to hurry.It's almost full. Please.
快来，快来，你们一定要尽快沙子就要灌满了
Paul, just hang in there.We're right above you.
保罗，你要坚持住。，我们就在你上面
I can't. I can't. Are you close?
我坚持不了了，你们到了吗？
- We're almost there!- Are you close?
- 快了！- 你们到了吗？
We're almost there! Right above!
快了！在你上面了！
- Please! Please! I can't hear you!- Keep digging!
- 求求你快点，我听不清你说什么- 继续挖
- I can't hear you! Where are you?- We're almost there!
- 我听不清你说什么，你们在哪？- 我们马上找到你了！
Keep digging! We see the coffin.
继续挖！我们看见棺材了
Yeah, dig in...
快挖
- Hang in there!- Please open it. Please open it.
- 坚持住！- 求求你快把棺材打开
Let's go! Move! Faster guys, faster!
快，快！大家快点挖，快！
- Hurry up! Hurry!- Okay, okay, clear!
- 快挖，快！- 好的，好的，我听见了
Fucking hurry! Please!
他妈的快挖啊！求求你！
Hurry!
快！
Oh, my God.
我的天
- What? What?- Oh, my God.
- 怎么了？怎么了？- 我的天
- I'm so sorry, Paul. I'm so sorry.- What is... What?
- 我很抱歉，保罗，我很抱歉- 怎么，怎么了？
It's Mark White.
我们挖到的是马克・怀特
He brought us to Mark White.
他把我们带到马克・怀特这来了
Oh, God. Oh, God
天呐，天呐
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.- Okay.
- 我很抱歉，我很抱歉- 好吧
Okay. Oh, God.
好吧，天啊
I'm sorry, Paul. I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉，保罗，真的非常抱歉